Xinyi Chen

+44 7536127587 | NW1, London

✓ xinyic2022@gmail.com | in linkedin.com/in/xinyi-c03 | O github.com/xinyichen03

Professional Summary

I am a skilled professional transitioning from a background in arts and media to technology and data. With a Comparative Literature degree from the University of Edinburgh and experience at CityMusic Promotions, I have developed practical programming skills, automating processes to enhance efficiency. Proficient in Python, SQLite3, Pandas, and Streamlit, I create tools to optimize workflows and support strategic decisions.

Work Experience

Marketing Analyst

Sep 2022 - Present

CityMusic Promotions, London

- Analyzed sales data by using MS Excel, SQLite3, and Pandas, a data manipulation and analysis library in Python, and used Streamlit to create dashboards to visualize sales data across 8 sites.
- Created a suite of Python web automation tools using Selenium that reduced manual processing time by 85%.
- Developed a Python program to streamline sales reporting and sales data collection, boosting efficiency by 70% and enhancing accuracy.
- Updated and amended web content on company website, managing events on multiple box office ticketing systems including Eventbrite, Skiddle, Eventim, SeeTickets, ClassicTics etc.
- Designed e-newsletters and graphics for email marketing and marketing on social media channels by using Canva and Photoshop, and used Mailchimp to launch email campaigns for 10,000+ subscribers, doubling click rates and surpassing industry benchmarks by 2.3%.
- Liaised with 20+ venues via email and social media, coordinating print marketing logistics and digital marketing initiatives.
- Achieved 100% accurate concert information listings for 600+ concerts across UK on 10+ discovery and ticketing platforms.

Editorial & Marketing Intern

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

China Translation & Publishing Corporation, Beijing

- Market Research: Conducted comprehensive market analysis that informed strategic decisions for 3 new book deals, resulting in a 20% increase in sales.
- Content Creation: Produced high-quality video content for social media platforms, growing the company's online following by 30% in three months.
- Editing and Proofreading: Edited and proofread over 10 manuscripts, ensuring the highest quality of publications.

Education

University of Edinburgh | Edinburgh, UK

Sep 2021 - Nov 2022

MSc Comparative Literature

Awarded with Merit

- Conference Speaker: 'Transposing Metatheatre: The Role of Art and Media Oct 2022 in Feng Xiaogang's The Banquet (2006) and Michael Almereyda's Hamlet (2000),' presented at II SEDERI International Conference for Junior Researchers of Early Modern English Studies, Autonomous University of Madrid (UAM), Spain http://www.sederi.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Programme.pdf
- **Publication:** '¡Hola Madrid! Presenting at My First Academic Conference' published on 'Intermediality: Literature, Film and the Arts in Dialogue Msc/PhD Programmes and Research Strand at the University of Edinburgh' https://blogs.ed.ac.uk/intermediality/blog/

University of California, Berkeley | Berkeley, CA, USA

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Berkeley International Study Program

GPA: 3.8/4.0 (First Class)

• Academic Excellence: Achieved straight A grades in Shakespeare, American Novel, Literature in English 1900-present, Feminist Theory, Children's Literature, The Greek Mythology

Minzu University of China | Beijing, China

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

BA English Language and Literature

GPA: 92.21/100 (First Class)

• **Leadership**: President of Media and Information Center of Students' Union, leading a 10-member cross-functional team to have organized successful major campus events boosting attendance by 40%.

Skills

Programming Skills

• Python, SQL, Selenium, Pandas, Steamlit, Markdown, BeautifulSoup, Git, Github, OpenAI API, LLM

Software Skills

- Office Suite: Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel; Google Sheets, Slides, Docs; Meta Business Suite
- Design Tools: Photoshop, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Canva, Mailchimp, Figma, Webflow

Soft Skills

• Customer Service, Communication, Leadership and Team Management, Presentation, Public Speaking, Problem-Solving

Languages

• English (fluent), Mandarin (native), French (conversational)

Certificate & Awards

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design (2024, Google)
- Introduction to Python & Apps (2024, Barclays, Code First Girls)
- Introduction to Marketing (2024, University of Pennsylvania)
- Fundamentals of Music Theory (2023, University of Edinburgh)
 MUC University Merit-Based (top 2%) Scholarship (2019)
- MUC University Merit-Based (top 2%) Scholarship (2019)
 MUC University Merit-Based (top 2%) Scholarship (2018)
- First-Prize Sociological Research on the Culture of Jun Porcelain in China (2019)
- First-Prize MUC English-Mandarin Translation Contest (2019)

Additional Experience

Team Leader

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

Caffè Nero, Edinburgh

- Customer Satisfaction: Maintained 99% customer satisfaction rate by implementing a new staff training program focused on customer service excellence.
- Operational Management: Streamlined inventory management processes, reducing waste and saving the store £5,000 annually.
 Sales Performance: Launched a promotional campaign for seasonal products that resulted in a 46% increase in sales

during the holiday season. **Art Installation Volunteer**

Jul 2022 - Jul 2022

National Museum of Scotland, Edinburgh

• Creative Contribution: Played a key role in crafting and installing art pieces for a major exhibit, George Nuku's installation art Bottled Ocean 2123, engaging directly with artistic process and enhancing the museum's visitor experience.

Sales Assistant Volunteer

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

British Heart Foundation, Edinburgh

• Customer Service: Assisted customers with inquiries and purchases, contributing to a 17% increase in store donations and 22% increase in Gift Aiders registration.